Sina Malek

Software Engineer

Personal Info

Address

Tucson, Arizona, USA

Phone

(602)-471-7084

Email

maleksina1998@gmail.com

Website

www.sinamalek.com

Skills

Python

C/C++

CMake

MATLAB

SCPI, YAML

Markdown, Doxygen

Git

Software

IDEs

Microsoft Visual Studio Visual Studio Code PyCharm Workbench Beyond Compare NI-MAX MATLAB Clonezilla

Text Editors

Notepad++

Microsoft Office

Excel PowerPoint OneNote Outlook Word Experienced software engineer in need of a full-time direct hire position with a dynamic company. Resolute collaborator with strong ethics who can work independently or with a team. Has experience in test software and architecture, clean up, ESMs, automation and producing standardizations for future software developments.

Experience

2021-05 -

Software Engineer I

Present

Raytheon Missile & Defense / Tucson, AZ

- Configured oscilloscopes, signal generators, signal analyzers, power supplies, FSWP, RF switch boxes to be compatible with internal software and able to communicate using SCPI and Python scripts to programs specifications.
- Using Azure DevOps, YAML and Python scripts, created automation process of BIT testing to ensure health of hardware.
- Saved the company time and money by a reducing the number of engineers needed when testing and delivering hardware stacks to programs. Created automated system to progress testing standard.
- Trained basic regression neural network with Henze-Penrose Divergence loss. Converted existing MATLAB scripts to Python and used existing NumPy data sets to determine loss.
- Updated software version through merge techniques and tools such as BeyondCompare and ensuring the entirety of the software remained functional.
- Established backlog, work items and sprint velocities, functioned as **Scrum Master** for team and product.

2019-05 -2019-10

IT Service Desk Intern

10 Amkor Technology Inc. / Tempe, AZ

- **Project leader** of Windows 7 to Windows 10 conversion for Tempe location.
- Collaborated with various departments to utilize **Clonezilla** to create standard computer image.
- Assisted in IT services to increase company output by providing technology support for all users; ensure users workstations function to company standard, and have thoroughly documented results for future reference.
- Implemented configuration and deployment of new equipment such as laptops, desktops, and phones.

Education

2016-05 -2020-05

Bachelor of Science in Engineering Computer Systems

Arizona State University / Tempe, AZ

- Graduated **Cum Laude**, 3.5 / 4.0
- Software Officer for Naval Research Laboratory CanSat competition. Placed **first** place amongst US teams.
- Studied AI/ML, OS, software architecture, networking, and embedded systems.